Let's start with an understanding of what this course is about and what it's not about.
فلنبدأ بفهم ما يدور حوله هذا البرنامج التدريبي وما لا يدور حوله.
One example of what this course is about is that here we will talk
وكمثال لما سنتحدث عنه خلال هذه الدورة التدريبية
about strategies to build up a good freelancing profile.
سنتحدث عن استراتيجيات إنشاء ملف شخصي قوي للموظف الحر.
Some best practices to find work from clients when we're starting out.
وأفضل الاستراتيجيات للعثور على عمل مع عملاء في بداية الطريق.
Strategies to work sustainably with clients.
واستراتيجيات العمل طويل الأمد مع العملاء.
Think of this course to be about kickstarting your freelancing career,
لتعتبر هذه الدورة التدريبية خطوة البداية في مجال عملك الحر،
how to get those first few clients and best practices,
وكيف تستطيع الحصول على العملاء في البداية، وستتعرف على أفضل الممارسات
tips and tricks to walk through as you continue in your freelancing journey.
والنصائح والأفكار التي تحتاجها في رحلة عملك الحر.
Different tools and platforms that are used.
وستعرف الأدوات والمنصات التي ستعمل عليها.
Real-life scenarios in a freelancing journey and how to deal with each of those.
وسنتناقش في سيناريوهات واقعية لرحلة العمل الحر وكيفية التعامل مع كل منها.
But here we won't be talking about things like what is freelancing or its pros and cons,
ولن نتحدث هنا عن أمور مثل: ما هو العمل الحر ولن نناقش إيجابياته وسلبياته،
because it is assumed that we already have a basic understanding of what is freelancing.
لأن من المفترض أن يكون لدينا بالفعل فهم أساسي للعمل الحر.
We will also not go through
ولن نستعرض
the logistical details of each freelancing platform individually,
التفاصيل اللوجستية لكل منصة عمل حر بشكل منفصل،
and would generally talk about the basics of
وسنتحدث بشكل عام عن أساسيات
a freelancing platform that would be handy for you when you work with any platform.
منصات العمل الحر التي ستفيدك عند العمل على أي منصة.
Now, let's quickly take a look at what do we need to know before we take on this course.
والآن سنلقي نظرة سريعة على ما نحتاج إلى معرفته قبل البدء في هذه الدورة التدريبية.
First, we need to know the fundamentals of digital freelancing.
أولاً، يتعين علينا أن نعرف أساسيات العمل الرقمي الحر.
What is freelancing and how it is different from a full-time job.
ما هو العمل الحر؟ وكيف يختلف عن العمل بنظام الدوام الكامل؟
Second, and the most important is that we need to
ثانيًا، الأمر الأهم هو أننا نحتاج أن يكون لدينا
have a skill that we can use to get work from clients.
مهارة يمكننا استخدامها للحصول على مهام من العملاء.
For example, you could build a website for
على سبيل المثال، يمكنك إنشاء موقع إلكتروني
a client or you could provide a digital marketing solution.
للعميل أو توفير حلول تسويقية إلكترونية.
You could also get an idea of the marketable skills that are popular by looking at some
يمكنك أيضاً التعرف على أهم المهارات القابلة للتسويق والتي تحظى بشعبية كبيرة من خلال النظر إلى بعض
of the freelancing platforms that we will cover in detail in this course.
منصات العمل الحر والتي سنتكلم عنها بالتفصيل خلال الدورة التدريبية.
Since you'll mostly be working remotely,
وبما أنك ستعمل غالبًا عن طريق الإنترنت،
it's good to have a stable Internet connection so you can have
فمن المهم أن يكون لديك اتصال إنترنت مستقر حتى تتمكن من تلقي
audio or video calls with clients comfortably,
مكالمات صوت أو فيديو مع العملاء بشكل مريح
and also be able to use online collaboration tools.
وكذلك القدرة على استخدام أدوات التعاون والتواصل عبر الإنترنت.
Since you will be mostly conversing in English,
بما أنك ستتحدث في الغالب باللغة الإنجليزية،
it's good to be able to speak and write English.
فمن المهم أن تكون قادرًا على التحدث والكتابة باللغة الإنجليزية.
It will also help if you can work on
وسيكون الوضع أفضل إذا كنت تستطيع العمل على
Microsoft Office products like Microsoft Word and Excel, or Google Workspace.
منتجات Microsoft Office مثل Microsoft Word وExcel أو Google Workspace.
Tools like Google Docs or Google Sheets,
وأدوات مثل Google Docs أو Google Sheets،
since they may be quite handy when working with clients on projects,
حيث أنها أدوات مفيدة جدًا عند العمل مع العملاء على مشاريع أو
documents, or service agreements.
مستندات أو اتفاقيات الخدمة.
Finally, it is recommended that you have completed
وأخيرًا، فمن الأفضل أن تكون قد حصلت على
one Nanodegree through Udacity with at least two projects successfully passed.
شهادة النانوديجري من شركة Udacity باجتياز مشروعين على الأقل.